

Designer & Researcher

jamesdavidmoffet.com

jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com

in jamesdavidmoffet

about

As a designer and researcher, I am obsessed with understanding the human mechanisms by which technology can deliver us into an alternative future. As a researcher, I have learned to temper this obsession, harnessing critical theory and a range of research and management techniques that help me to redirect the internal inertia of established organizations and to find room to apply systems-level, user-centered thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's lives.

education

2016 - 2018

Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's Degree Design Studies in Technology

SKIIS

UI/UX Design
User Research
Service Design
Public Speaking
Product Management
Machine Learning
R, SPSS, Python, Torch
Software Engineering
Hardware Engineering

work experience

SEIU International

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA Senior Product Manager
 Led team producing user research and interface design, hired and managed engineers for cloud-hosted financial and membership data system handling 25M records, 50 corporate partners and \$5M.

Fulbright Fellow

2015 - 2016 Budapest, HU Lecturer / Researcher
 Community design education at the
 Center for Media, Data and Society in
 Budapest. Piloted OpenLab workshops,
 coached and mentored UXR, interface
 design and tech prototyping for public
 projects out of FabLab Budapest.

MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA

UXR / UXD Manager Managed a democratic capacity mapping and toolbuilding project for the MIT Community Innovators lab. Oversaw research labor, designed and engineered a democratic capacity mapping and organizational partnership tool.

Civic Tech Fellow

Summer 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA

UXR / UXD Manager Developed civic technology for the City of Cambridge, focusing on easy to deploy open source citizen analytics apps and consulted for GoINVO on the MA SNAP application redesign.

OutVote.io & Commit.vote - Founder / Interaction Chief

2017 - 2018 Cambridge, MA, USA

Founded civic tech startup COMM!T a tool for peer-enforced smart contracts to drive civic participation. Acquired by OutVote civic networking app Nov. 2017. Currently owning UX for a product with

10 enterprise clients.